Benjamin Banwart

Fort Scott, Kansas

Benjibanwart@gmail.com | (620)404-2094 | LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio Site

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Software Engineer with experience in full-stack web development including front-end, back-end, and testing. Currently attending a software engineering boot camp with KSU. Most efficient when working and collaborating with others. Avid lifetime learner and passionate about exceptional visual design and functionality.

EDUCATION

Kansas State University

Manhattan, KS

Software Development Professional Certificate

Graduate in July of 2022

Courses: Front-End Development, UI-UX, Back-End Development and APIs, React-Redux, SQL and Data Modeling, MERN-stack Project, Principles of Programming in Python, Advanced Programming Topics

SKILLS PROFILE

Certification: Software Engineer

Development Technologies: JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, Flask, CSS, SASS, SCSS, HTML, AWS, GitHub, PgAdmin, C#, PSQL, Sequelize, APIs, Jinja, Git, React, Redux, NodeJS, Express, Bootstrap Material-UI, Mongoose,

Axios, macOS, Linux Databases: MongoDB, PostgreSQL

Deployment Tools: GitHub Pages, Heroku, Netlify, ElephantSQL, MongoDB Atlas, Amazon S3 Bucket, AWS Elastic

Beanstalk, CircleCI

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

REST-Rant March 2022

- Created a full-stack application that allows users to review restaurants.
- The app is hosted on Heroku and uses MongoDB as a database.
- Development technologies include JavaScript, Bootstrap, MongoDB, Express, NodeJS, JSX, and express-react-views.

MERNstagram May 2022

- Created a PERN-stack application in collaboration with three other classmates for a group milestone project.
- Create, view, edit, and delete social media posts with this application.
- The app is hosted in three places: the client is hosted on Netlify, the server is hosted on Heroku, and the Database is hosted with ElephantSQL.
- Development technologies include JavaScript, Material-UI, PostgreSQL, React, Git, ElephantSQL, PgAdmin, Axios, Express, NodeJS, and JSX.
- This project was instrumental in showing all of my group and I how to function as a team and properly use all of the different version control features of git.

Music API April 2022

- Created a JavaScript API for a music tour.
- Users can send requests, use all CRUD operations, and view responses rendered as JSON in the browser.
- Demonstrates a relational database with many tables.

API uses PostgreSQL as a database and implements Sequelize as an ODM.

NASA API Image Implementation

February 2022 • Created a web page that

utilizes the NASA APOD API, JavaScript, and minimalist CSS styling.

• The page updates daily with a new image of space and a description of said image along with the title, author, and copyrights.

Pokemon_Battle_Game

January 2022–February 2022

- Created a fully-functional browser Pokémon battle game using raw HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- The JavaScript logic allows for a user to choose his or her party of Pokémon and then battle against a computer player until the user wins or loses.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Hairbow Center, Fort Scott, KS

February 2020–Present

Catalog Listing Assistant

- List highly detailed and niche products on Amazon, Etsy, Walmart
- Communicate regularly with the product analyst and the sales department in creating the varying products with details that are oriented for sales optimization

Hairbow Center, Fort Scott, KS

April 2014-February 2020

Warehouse Laborer

- Worked in product production and conversion
- Converted large product units to multiple smaller product units while operating a machine
- Kept shelves saturated with products for pickers
- Troubleshot inventory errors using an online SKU-based inventory management system and communication with co-workers